=Within The Grip=
=ภายในด้ามจับ=
=Episode 4=
= ตอนที่ 4=
(Mute Husband)
(สามีใบ้)
Yuluo, you've become even prettier.
Yuluo คุณสวยขึ้นอีก
It's you.
คุณเอง.
Why are you so mean to me?
ทำไมคุณถึงใจร้ายกับฉันขนาดนี้?
(Gu Xuanji, Second Young Miss of the Gu family)
(กู่ซวนจี๋, คุณหนูคนที่สองของตระกูล Gu)
Search carefully. Don't let them escape.
ค้นหาอย่างระมัดระวัง อย่าปล่อยให้พวกเขาหลบหนี
My dear sister-in-law, I'll let you handle it.
น้องสะใภ้ที่รักของฉัน ฉันจะปล่อยให้คุณจัดการมัน
How come it's you?
เป็นคุณได้ยังไง?
Why are you so agitated, dear?
ทำไมคุณถึงกระวนกระวายใจขนาดนี้ที่รัก?
Why are you here?
ทำไมคุณถึงอยู่ที่นี่?
It's chilly at night.
ตอนกลางคืนอากาศหนาวเย็น
You've been out for quite a while.
คุณออกไปข้างนอกมาสักพักแล้ว
You said you and your husband are deeply in love.
คุณบอกว่าคุณและสามีของคุณ มีความรักอย่างลึกซึ้ง
He surely wouldn't leave you out there alone.
เขาคงไม่ทำอย่างนั้นอย่างแน่นอน ปล่อยให้คุณอยู่ที่นั่นตามลำพัง
Therefore, I brought you a cloak.
ข้าพเจ้าจึงนำเสื้อคลุมมาให้ท่าน
You don't have to act like this when it's just the two of us.
คุณไม่จำเป็นต้องทำตัวแบบนี้ เมื่อมันมีแค่เราสองคน
But right now, it's not just the two of us.
แต่ในตอนนี้ ไม่ใช่แค่เราสองคน
Yuluo.
ยูลัว.
Are you alright?
คุณสบายดีไหม?
Examine the bodies. Take them to the authorities.
ตรวจร่างกาย. พาพวกเขาไปให้เจ้าหน้าที่
- Understood.
- เข้าใจแล้ว.
Let's go find Xuanji.
ไปหาซวนจีกันเถอะ
Weren't you expecting that molten iron flower show?
คุณไม่ได้คาดหวัง การแสดงดอกไม้เหล็กหลอมนั้นเหรอ?
If we miss it this time, who knows when the next chance will be.
หากพลาดครั้งนี้ ใครจะรู้ว่าโอกาสครั้งต่อไปจะเกิดขึ้นเมื่อใด
Take a look, young master.
ลองดูครับอาจารย์หนุ่ม
Yuluo, this suits you well. Do you like it?
Yuluo นี่เหมาะกับคุณมาก คุณชอบมันไหม?
You have a keen eye. This is a Yin-Yang Twin-Blade Dagger.
คุณมีสายตาที่กระตือรือร้น นี่คือกริชใบมีดแฝดหยินหยาง
Press the gemstones.
กดพลอย.
Pressing the red gem ejects the blade. Pressing the blue one retracts it.
การกดอัญมณีสีแดงจะปลดใบมีดออก การกดอันสีน้ำเงินจะดึงกลับ
Only five taels of silver.
เงินเพียงห้าตำลึงเท่านั้น
What's so special about it? Who gives a dagger to a woman?
มีอะไรพิเศษเกี่ยวกับเรื่องนี้? ใครให้กริชแก่ผู้หญิง?
I like it very much.
ฉันชอบมันมาก
Thank you.
ขอบคุณ
You're in a good mood.
คุณอารมณ์ดี
You were just being hunted down.
คุณแค่ถูกตามล่า
Now you have the leisure to have tea?
ตอนนี้คุณมีเวลาว่างที่จะดื่มชาแล้วหรือยัง?
Thank you for saving me.
ขอบคุณที่ช่วยฉัน
I toast to you.
ฉันอวยพรให้คุณ
Why were you there?
ทำไมคุณถึงอยู่ที่นั่น?
I'm planning to open a new tavern in the city.
ฉันกำลังวางแผนอยู่ เพื่อเปิดโรงเตี๊ยมแห่งใหม่ในเมือง
Zuixian Building happens to be for transfer, so I took over.
อาคาร Zuixian เกิดขึ้นได้ เพื่อการโอนจึงรับช่วงต่อ
I wanted to announce it during the Lantern Festival.
ฉันต้องการที่จะประกาศมัน ในช่วงเทศกาลโคมไฟ
But unfortunately, things went wrong.
แต่น่าเสียดายที่สิ่งต่าง ๆ ผิดพลาด
For transfer?
สำหรับการโอน?
Yes, I heard the owner is going home to get married a few days ago.
ใช่ ฉันได้ยินมาว่าเจ้าของกำลังจะกลับบ้าน ที่จะแต่งงานเมื่อไม่กี่วันก่อน
Why did she have to transfer the tavern for that?
ทำไมเธอถึงต้อง ย้ายโรงเตี๊ยมเพื่อสิ่งนั้นเหรอ?
You seem quite concerned about her.
ดูเหมือนคุณค่อนข้างจะกังวลเกี่ยวกับเธอ
I just find it odd, that's all.
ฉันแค่คิดว่ามันแปลกก็แค่นั้น
Speaking of which, when is your wedding?
เมื่อพูดถึงงานแต่งงานของคุณเมื่อไหร่?
A storm is brewing.
พายุกำลังก่อตัว
Let's set it for
มาตั้งค่าให้
one month from now.
หนึ่งเดือนต่อจากนี้
Zhaoxi's health condition...
ภาวะสุขภาพของ Zhaoxi...
I can't wait that long.
ฉันไม่สามารถรอนานขนาดนั้น
You'll surely recover soon.
คุณจะฟื้นตัวในไม่ช้าอย่างแน่นอน
One more thing.
อีกสิ่งหนึ่ง
Master Zhaoxi has just returned with injuries.
อาจารย์จ้าวซี เพิ่งกลับมาพร้อมอาการบาดเจ็บ
If anyone comes to visit...
หากใครมาเยือน...
It's up to you.
มันขึ้นอยู่กับคุณ
Understood.
เข้าใจแล้ว.
In a month.
ในหนึ่งเดือน
What?
อะไร
So soon?
เร็ว ๆ นี้?
The original date was nearly two months away.
วันที่เดิม อยู่ห่างออกไปเกือบสองเดือน
In one month,
ในหนึ่งเดือน
I'm not sure if my Nichang Workshop can finish the garments.
ฉันไม่แน่ใจว่า Nichang Workshop ของฉันหรือเปล่า สามารถตัดเย็บเสื้อผ้าให้เสร็จได้
Don't we have the wedding gown ready?
เราเตรียมชุดแต่งงานไว้แล้วไม่ใช่เหรอ?
Charging into the funeral hall in your wedding gown was quite a tale.
บุกเข้าไปในห้องฌาปนกิจ ในชุดแต่งงานของคุณค่อนข้างเป็นเรื่องเล่า
But it's better to replace it since it's seen the funeral hall.
แต่จะดีกว่าถ้าแทนที่ เนื่องจากเห็นโถงงานศพ
(Brother Gu Zhaoxi's Spirit Tablet)
(แผ่นจารึกวิญญาณของพี่ชาย Gu Zhaoxi)
No need.
ไม่จำเป็น.
So you refuse to accept my goodwill?
แล้วคุณปฏิเสธที่จะยอมรับความปรารถนาดีของฉันเหรอ?
That's not it.
นั่นไม่ใช่มัน
Let us get your measurements for a new set of garments, Zhaoxi.
ให้เราได้รับการวัดของคุณ สำหรับเสื้อผ้าชุดใหม่ จ้าวซี
In that case, we'll trouble you, Xuanji.
ในกรณีนั้น เราจะรบกวนคุณเอง ซวนจี
Don't mention it, Yuluo.
อย่าพูดถึงมันเลย ยูลัว
Creating garments for a beauty is a great pleasure.
สร้างสรรค์เสื้อผ้าให้สวยงาม เป็นความยินดีอย่างยิ่ง
But Zhaoxi, we haven't seen each other for five years.
แต่ Zhaoxi เราไม่มี เจอกันมาห้าปีแล้ว
How come you don't speak to me at all?
ทำไมคุณไม่พูดกับฉันเลย?
Do you disdain speaking to an outsider like me?
คุณรังเกียจการพูด ถึงคนนอกเช่นฉันเหรอ?
Zhaoxi, you haven't recovered yet. It's all my fault.
จ้าวซี คุณยังไม่หายดีเลย มันเป็นความผิดของฉันทั้งหมด
Let me take you back.
ให้ฉันพาคุณกลับ
(Wanfeng Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
(ศาลาว่านเฟิง, คฤหาสน์กู่)
So,
ดังนั้น
those assassins fled into Xuanji's courtyard?
มือสังหารเหล่านั้นหนีไป เข้าไปในลานบ้านของ Xuanji?
Yes, but I didn't hear any sounds of fighting.
ใช่แต่ฉันไม่ได้ยิน เสียงการต่อสู้ใดๆ
By the time I went for a closer look, the assassins had vanished.
พอผมเข้าไปดูใกล้ๆ พวกนักฆ่าก็หายตัวไป
Are you saying that Xuanji sent those assassins?
คุณกำลังพูด ที่ซวนจีส่งนักฆ่าพวกนั้นมาเหรอ?
Were they after Xuanji
พวกเขาตามล่า Xuanji
or that shop owner?
หรือเจ้าของร้านคนนั้น?
I can't tell.
ฉันไม่สามารถบอกได้
How is his wound?
บาดแผลของเขาเป็นยังไงบ้าง?
Wound?
แผล?
I asked him to take a medicinal bath.
ฉันขอให้เขาไปอาบน้ำยา
Reckless.
ประมาท.
It's time?
ถึงเวลาแล้วเหรอ?
Xuan Qing doesn't know about your injury, but you do.
ซวนชิงไม่รู้ เกี่ยวกับอาการบาดเจ็บของคุณ แต่คุณทำ
Let me change your dressing.
ให้ฉันเปลี่ยนการแต่งตัวของคุณ
Is this how you treat your husband too?
นี่เป็นวิธีที่คุณปฏิบัติต่อสามีของคุณด้วยเหรอ?
Back when I was injured, he comforted me like this.
ย้อนกลับไปตอนที่ฉันได้รับบาดเจ็บ พระองค์ทรงปลอบโยนข้าพเจ้าเช่นนี้
This is a couple's thing. You don't have to understand.
นี่มันเป็นเรื่องของคู่รัก คุณไม่จำเป็นต้องเข้าใจ
Just focus on playing your part.
เพียงแค่มุ่งเน้นไปที่การเล่นในส่วนของคุณ
You did well today.
วันนี้คุณทำได้ดีแล้ว
A couple's thing.
เรื่องของคู่รัก.
Barging in while someone is bathing
ทะเลาะกันในขณะที่มีคนอาบน้ำ
counts as a couple's thing?
นับเป็นเรื่องของคู่รักเหรอ?
I knocked.
ฉันเคาะ
Besides,
นอกจากนี้
if I hadn't barged in,
ถ้าฉันไม่ได้บุกเข้ามา
someone's wound would've festered.
บาดแผลของใครบางคนคงจะเปื่อยเน่า
It occurs to me that you're much more likable
มันเกิดขึ้นกับฉัน ว่าคุณน่ารักกว่ามาก
when you're quiet.
เมื่อคุณเงียบ
Isn't that right, my mute husband?
ใช่มั้ยสามีใบ้ของฉัน?
Tomorrow, I'll teach you how to talk like him.
พรุ่งนี้ฉันจะสอนคุณ พูดยังไงให้เหมือนเขา
So many eyes on the Fufeng Pavilion.
มีสายตามากมายไปที่ศาลา Fufeng
We've caught 13 people and sent them for interrogation.
เราจับได้ 13 คน และส่งตัวไปสอบสวน
But I may need to lie low for a while.
แต่ฉันอาจต้องนอนต่ำสักพัก
That courtyard guard has sharp hearing.
ยามสนามนั่นมีการได้ยินที่เฉียบคม
I tried sneaking in and almost got caught several times.
ฉันพยายามแอบเข้าไป และเกือบโดนจับหลายครั้ง
Got anything useful?
มีอะไรที่เป็นประโยชน์บ้างไหม?
They're keeping tight-lipped.
พวกเขาเม้มปากแน่น
But rest assured, they'll crack in three days.
แต่มั่นใจได้เลยว่า พวกเขาจะแตกในสามวัน
Three days?
สามวัน?
Kill him.
ฆ่าเขา.
I confess.
ฉันสารภาพ.
(Watch the Fufeng Pavilion)
(ชมศาลา Fufeng)
Master, what about these people?
อาจารย์ แล้วคนพวกนี้ล่ะ?
I never keep useless people around. Dispose of them.
ฉันไม่เคยเก็บคนไร้ประโยชน์ไว้รอบตัว กำจัดพวกมัน
Understood.
เข้าใจแล้ว.
Why is that person so fixated on Fufeng Pavilion?
ทำไมเป็นคนๆนั้น. จับจ้องไปที่ศาลา Fufeng มากขนาดนั้นเลยเหรอ?
But it seems he's not siding with the Gu family.
แต่ดูเหมือนว่า เขาไม่ได้เข้าข้างตระกูล Gu
Forget about the spies at Fufeng Pavilion.
ลืมเกี่ยวกับสายลับ ณ ศาลาฟูเฟิง
Stop patrolling the area for a few days.
หยุดลาดตระเวนพื้นที่สักสองสามวัน
Understood.
เข้าใจแล้ว.
(Fufeng Pavilion, Gu Mansion)
(ศาลา Fufeng, คฤหาสน์ Gu)
Things have quieted down these days.
สิ่งต่างๆ ได้เงียบลงในวันนี้
You haven't spotted any spies?
คุณไม่เห็นสายลับเลยเหรอ?
None.
ไม่มี.
Though someone has been lingering outside.
แม้ว่ามีใครเคยเป็นก็ตาม ยังคงอยู่ข้างนอก
Exceptional lightness skills.
ทักษะความเบาที่ยอดเยี่ยม
I haven't been able to track him down yet.
ฉันไม่สามารถ ติดตามเขาลงยัง
Since my "husband" arrived, I've had much more free time.
ตั้งแต่ “สามี” ของฉันมาถึง ฉันมีเวลาว่างมากขึ้น
Seems I should pay him a visit.
ดูเหมือนว่าฉันควรจะไปเยี่ยมเขานะ
(Vast Mind, Eternal Will)
(ใจกว้างใหญ่ เจตจำนงนิรันดร์)
Is this how you knocked yesterday?
เมื่อวานคุณเคาะแบบนี้เหรอ?
Why did you come so early today?
ทำไมวันนี้คุณมาเร็วจัง?
Didn't I tell you I'd teach you how to speak?
ฉันไม่ได้บอกคุณเหรอ ฉันจะสอนคุณพูดยังไง?
To imitate someone is not just to look like them.
เพื่อเลียนแบบใครสักคน ไม่ใช่แค่ทำให้ดูเหมือนพวกเขาเท่านั้น
It requires observation.
มันต้องมีการสังเกต
Imitate their moves, vocal patterns, and speech mannerisms
เลียนแบบการเคลื่อนไหวของพวกเขา รูปแบบเสียงร้องและกิริยาท่าทางในการพูด
in the shortest time possible.
ในเวลาอันสั้นที่สุด
But you've never met Zhaoxi.
แต่คุณไม่เคยพบกับ Zhaoxi
So you can only rely on my descriptions.
ดังนั้นคุณจึงสามารถพึ่งพาคำอธิบายของฉันได้เท่านั้น
In that case, you must avoid people to stay safe.
ในกรณีนี้คุณต้อง หลีกเลี่ยงผู้คนเพื่อให้ปลอดภัย
Like this.
แบบนี้.
Zhaoxi has always been ill.
Zhaoxi ป่วยมาตลอด
Temperatures bearable for most people would burn him.
อุณหภูมิที่สามารถทนได้สำหรับคนส่วนใหญ่ จะเผาเขา
So hold the tea saucer when accepting tea.
เลยถือจานรองน้ำชาไว้ เมื่อรับชา.
That's your first lesson.
นั่นเป็นบทเรียนแรกของคุณ
Finish the tea, then I'll teach you how to talk like him.
ชาเสร็จแล้วฉันจะสอนคุณ พูดยังไงให้เหมือนเขา
I was going to ask you to blow on it and sip slowly.
ฉันกำลังจะถามคุณ เป่ามันแล้วจิบช้าๆ
But you're quick to improvise.
แต่คุณก็ด้นสดอย่างรวดเร็ว
Dear.
ที่รัก.
Your hairpin is crooked.
กิ๊บของคุณคดเคี้ยว
What's wrong, dear?
มีอะไรผิดปกติที่รัก?
Nothing.
ไม่มีอะไร.
It's just that since you arrived,
มันเป็นอย่างนั้นตั้งแต่คุณมาถึง
things have quieted down in this courtyard.
สิ่งต่างๆ ได้สงบลงแล้ว ในลานนี้
Now let me teach you how to speak like Zhaoxi.
ตอนนี้ให้ฉันสอนคุณ พูดยังไงให้เหมือนจ้าวซี
Keep your voice light, not too deep.
รักษาเสียงให้เบาไม่ลึกจนเกินไป
♪Willows sway in the twilight breeze♪
♪ต้นหลิวพลิ้วไหวในสายลมยามพลบค่ำ♪
♪Ancient alleys guard time's secrets♪
♪ตรอกซอกซอยโบราณคอยรักษาความลับของกาลเวลา♪
♪Bluestones bear life's imprints♪
♪หินบลูสโตนมีรอยประทับแห่งชีวิต♪
♪Falling petals, endless longing♪
♪กลีบร่วงหล่น ความปรารถนาอันไม่สิ้นสุด♪
♪Longing lingers within my heart♪
♪ความปรารถนายังคงอยู่ในใจฉัน♪
♪Zither strings sigh for the sorrow parting♪
♪ สายพิณถอนใจ สำหรับการจากลาอันแสนเศร้า♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪เรื่องราวในอดีตฝังอยู่ในจิตวิญญาณของฉัน♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪ความรักยังคงอยู่ มิอาจลืมเลือน♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪ม้วนหนังสือที่เปื้อนหมึกหวนคิดถึงอดีต♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪แต่ละจังหวะมีความคิด♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪ความเจริญรุ่งเรืองจางหายไปเหมือนความฝัน♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪เรื่องราวในอดีตฝังอยู่ในจิตวิญญาณของฉัน♪
♪Affection lingers, unforgettable♪
♪ความรักยังคงอยู่ มิอาจลืมเลือน♪
♪Ink-stained scrolls recall bygones♪
♪ม้วนหนังสือที่เปื้อนหมึกหวนคิดถึงอดีต♪
♪Each stroke holds a thought♪
♪แต่ละจังหวะมีความคิด♪
♪Prosperity fades like dreams♪
♪ความเจริญรุ่งเรืองจางหายไปเหมือนความฝัน♪
♪Past tales nest in my soul♪
♪ เรื่องราวในอดีตฝังอยู่ในจิตวิญญาณของฉัน ♪